MEZEKR WELDU Full-stack web developer

J +49(0)1764-4546546 ■ mezekr.weldu@tutamail.com LinkedIn GitHub Portfolio Frankfurt (Main)

SUMMARY

Acquired practical experience and honed skills in developing responsive web apps / websites and mobile apps with React Native by successfully completing CareerFoundry's 900+ hour project-based full-stack web development certification program. Additionally has a background in data processing and machine learning. Now seeks an opportunity in web development to tackle complex challenges and deliver bespoke solutions.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-end: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS, ReactJS, Angular, Redux, AJAX, ¡Query, Material, SASS, Tailwind CSS, Boot-

strap, Jest, Cucumber, Puppeteer, User Stories, User Flow, Wireframes

Back-end: NodeJS, Express, SQL, MongoDB, RESTful API, JSON, PostgreSQL, MySQL,

ML/DP: Python, Numpy, matplotlip, plotly, Scipy, Libros, Jupyter Notebook

Dev Tools: AWS, Git, GitHub/GitLab, Docker, CI/CD, VScode, WSL, Ubuntu, Vite, Webpack, Jira, Postman

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer 03/2023 - 07/2023

Pulsotronic GmbH & Co. through FERCHAU GmbH, Niederdorf / Chemnitz

- Designed and implemented a software module for data pre-processing and signal analysis resulted more accurate frequency analysis
- Gained hands-on experience of the basics of PLC programming on the PLCnext Controller with Ladder Diagrams (LD) for sensor data acquisition and processing
- Tech-Stack: Python, Pandas, Scipy, Librosa, Git, Gitlab, Jupyter Notebook, Plotly, Jira

Python Developer as Research & Teaching Assistant TU Bergakademie Freiberg , Freiberg (Saxony)

12/2020 - 06/2022

- Researched how collaborative learning in computer science can didactically developed and supported with digital media
- Streamlined data retrieval by developing a Python package to retrieve open source repository data from GitHub using REST API. This resulted in efficient data storage for analysis
- Analyzed the data to investigate the collaborative learning of programming for computer science students and non-computer science students
- · Created an algorithm to address the GitHub RestAPI rate limit, optimized data handling and fetching time
- Tech-Stack: Python, Pandas, Git, GitHub, GitHub REST-API, Jupyter Notebook

Information Communication Technology Teacher Sembel secondary school (Sss) ,Asmara

09/2013 - 07/2014

- Expanded and maintained the school's local area network, providing more staff and students with access to e-learning resources
- Improved learning outcomes by increasing access to IT resources for staff and students by 40%, resulting in a richer educational experience.

SELECTED WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

MeziFlix-app (Back-end) | Source Code

Nodejs | Express | MongoDB | Docker

- Crafted business logic for the server-side application, providing an API for easy storage and management of movies and user data.
- Implemented the RESTful API using Node.js, Express, MongoDB and integrated Passport for authentication and JWT for authorization.
- Tech-Stack: JavaScript, Nodejs, Express, MongoDB Atlas, mongosh, REST-API, JSON Insomnia, Git, GitHub, Docker

MeziFlix | Web app | Source Code

ReactJS | Bootstrap | SASS

- Developed a responsive ReactJs single page application that allows users to search and view movie info. Users can also create/edit/delete an account and add/remove movies to/from favorites
- Implemented the RESTful API provided by the "MeziFlix-app" backend App
- Tech-Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, Material, Git, GitHub, RESTful-API, Docker

Mezimeet App | Website | Source Code

- ReactJS | Jest | Puppeteer | Jest
- crafted a PWA that allows users to discover events in cities around the world, view event details and filter events by city or number
- Developed applying TDD methodology, including unit, integration and end-to-end testing
- Implemented OAuth 2.0 with Google using AWS Lambda serverless function, Google Calendar API to retrieve upcoming events
- Tech-Stack: JavaScript, React, CSS, SASS, Jest, Puppeteer, Cucumber, Recharts

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development Certificate CareerFoundry, Berlin (Remote)

12/2023 - 10/2024

- 900+ hours of immersive, project-based training that prioritizes best practices, guided by an industry-leading tutor and mentor
- Focused on JavaScript, Typescript, HTML, CSS and frameworks / libraries including React, Angular, Nodejs, Express, MongoDB and React Native for mobile app development
- Completed 6+ hands-on projects on the web technologies stack, resulting in the development of interactive and responsive web apps and implementing appealing to UX/UI

Master of Science in Applied Computer Science TU Bergakademie Freiberg, Freiberg (Saxony)

10/2019 - 09/2022

• Focus areas: Artificial Intelligence, Distributed systems, Virtual reality

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering Eritrean Institute of Technology, Mai-Nefhi

09/2008 -07/2013

• Focus areas: Software Engineering, Networking, Embedded Systems

ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATION

Languages: German, fluent written and spoken (C1) | English, fluent written and spoken

Driver's license: European type B